<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Saad Aouad</title>
    <link>https://saadaouad.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Saad Aouad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://saadaouad.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Redux</title>
      <link>https://saadaouad.net/post/what-is-redux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saadaouad.net/post/what-is-redux/</guid>
      <description>Redux is a JavaScript library that aims to manage stateful data. The state of your whole application is stored in a single JS object called store. A single function, the reducer, is responsible for making modifications to the store. We trigger the reducer by dispatching an action, a JS object that describes how our data should change. The reducer function receives the action as an argument and makes changes accordingly. Other parts of the code (usually React Components) can subscribe to data in the store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create React App</title>
      <link>https://saadaouad.net/post/create-react-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saadaouad.net/post/create-react-app/</guid>
      <description>You don’t need to install or configure tools like Webpack or Babel&amp;hellip; They are preconfigured and hidden so that you can focus just on the code!
 Getting Started Installation npm install -g create-react-app  or
yarn global add create-react-app  Create app To create a new app make you sure to run
create-react-app my-app cd my-app  Try to open the current folder in your editor, you should see the initial structure below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go HUGO - Fast and flexible static site generator build with GoLang</title>
      <link>https://saadaouad.net/post/go-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saadaouad.net/post/go-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators. With its amazing speed and flexibility, Hugo makes building websites fun again.
 Quick Start Step 1: Install Hugo  Homebrew, a package manager for macOS, can be installed from brew.sh. See install if you are running Windows etc.
 brew install hugo  Verify installation:
hugo version  Step 2: Create a New Site Create a new Hugo site in a folder named GoHugo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never stop learning</title>
      <link>https://saadaouad.net/post/never-stop-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saadaouad.net/post/never-stop-learning/</guid>
      <description>Never stop learning They never show that, they never teach that in school, you get your degree and then you work from 9am to 5pm, you go to the home, No! Every good engineer, i guarantee you they go home, they work, they study, so that when it comes time to learn new things, they know all about it already. And that, to me, is my road to mastery for any sort of technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://saadaouad.net/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://saadaouad.net/resume/</guid>
      <description>Education/Qualifications 2014-2015 Graduate school of management (ESG), Master 1 of information systems management, information systems.
2013-2014 Graduate school of management (ESG), License in information systems management, information systems.
2011-2013 ISGI-OFPPT, Technician specialized in IT-development.
Work Experience September/2016 - Current Front-End Developer at JoinCoded, Kuwait (Working remotely).
December/2015 - August/2016 Front-End Developer at OBytes, Morocco.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>